Finding aid to the Marjory Gane, Class of 1901 papers CA.MS.00398
Smith College Archives
Marjory Gane, Class of 1901 papers
1896-1990
Smith College Archives
Harkness, Marjory Gane, 1880 - 1974
CA.MS.00398
0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
Alumna. Contains about 140 letters to and from Gane's family and a memorabilia book created during Gane's undergraduate career at Smith College.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown
Biographical / Historical
Marjory Gane (1880 - 1974) was born in Yonkers, New York on March 8, 1880 to Sarah Jones and Thomas Gane, a book binder. The family later moved to Chicago, where Marjory attended Kirkland School before entering Smith College in 1897. Her sister Gertrude had attended Smith and graduated in 1894.
She married Frank Harkness in 1918 and the couple lived in Wonalancet, New Hampshire. After her husband's death in 1934, she opened and operated a real estate business and traveled until her death in 1974. A devoted alumna, Gane commissioned artist Henry Salem Hubbell to paint the portrait of L. Clark Seelye which hangs today in Alumnae House. She continued to contribute to many periodicals and published several books including A Brook of Our Own, The Fishbasket Papers and The Tamworth Narrative.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence and a memorabilia book describing the student life and perspective from Marjory Gane, Class of 1901. Topics range broadly from exams to professors, college and community social events, basketball and dramatics, cross-college events at Amherst College and Mount Holyoke, home life and trips to large cities such as New York City and Boston.
personal correspondence; scrapbooks; Harkness, Marjory Gane, 1880 - 1974; Smith College--Students-Correspondence; Smith College--Students--History-Sources; Smith College--Students--Social life and customs; Smith College--Alumni and alumnae.
- summaries of letters, 1990 (Box 1608, Folder 1)
- correspondence, 1897-09-03-1897-10-06 (Box 1608, Folder 2)
- correspondence, 1897-10-10-1897-11-11 (Box 1608, Folder 3)
- correspondence, 1897-11-14-1898-01-15 (Box 1608, Folder 4)
- correspondence, 1898-01-19-1898-02-06 (Box 1608, Folder 5)
- correspondence, 1898-02-13-1898-03-13 (Box 1608, Folder 6)
- correspondence, 1898-03-24-1898-04-24 (Box 1608, Folder 7)
- correspondence, 1898-05-01-1898-05-25 (Box 1608, Folder 8)
- correspondence, 1898-09-24-1898-11-20 (Box 1608, Folder 9)
- correspondence, 1898-11-30-1899-01-15 (Box 1608, Folder 10)
- correspondence, 1899-01-24-1899-02-24 (Box 1608, Folder 11)
- correspondence, 1899-02-26-1899-03-27 (Box 1608, Folder 12)
- correspondence, 04/30/1899 - 06/05/1899 (Box 1608, Folder 13)
- correspondence, 11/25/1899 - 01/28/1900 (Box 1608, Folder 14)
- correspondence, 02/26/1900 - 05/03/1900 (Box 1608, Folder 15)
- correspondence, 05/06/1900 - 06/01/1900 (Box 1608, Folder 16)
- correspondence, 09/23/1900 - 12/16/1900 (Box 1608, Folder 17)
- correspondence, 01/06/1901 - 02/24/1901 (Box 1608, Folder 18)
- correspondence, 03/07/1901 - 06/10/1901 (Box 1608, Folder 19)
- memorabilia book, 1900 (Box 1609, Folder 20)